Dearborn, Frederick M. (Frederick Myers), b. 1876, collector. Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy, 1832-1915 (MS Am 1649.24): Guide.
Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy,
- Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1803-1862. Printed D.s.; [n.p.] 1 Feb 1859., (469); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnston, George Doherty, 1832-1910. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Charleston, 25 Feb 1888., (470); 1s.(1p.)
- Johnston, Joseph Eggleston, 1807-1891. 2 A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard:
  - Manassas, 11 Sep 1861., (471); 1s.(4p.)
  - Centreville, 29 Jan 1862., (472); 1s.(2p.)
- Johnston, Joseph Eggleston, 1807-1891. 3 A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Centreville, 22 Nov 1861., (473); 1s.(3p.)
  - Rappahannock Bridge, 13 Mar 1862., (474); 1s.(3p.)
  - Tullahoma, 12 Feb 1863., (475); 1s.(1p.)
    The latter is a fragment only.
- Johnston, Joseph Eggleston, 1807-1891. A.L.s. to George Washington Custis Lee; Dalton, 11 Feb 1864., (476); 1s.(3p.)
- Johnston, Joseph Eggleston, 1807-1891. Printed D. (unsigned); Brandon, Miss., 22 Dec 1863., (477); 1s.(1p.)
  With printed D. (unsigned) by Leonidas Polk; Meridian, 23 Dec 1863. 1s.(1p.)
- Johnston, Robert Daniel, 1837-1919. A.L.s. to []; Birmingham, 14 Apr 1893., (478)
- Johnston, William Preston, 1831-1899. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Gainesville, Ky., 26 Apr 1861., (479); 1s.(3p.)
- Jones, A. C. A.L.s. to Henry Martyn Cist; Chin-Kiang, 31 Oct 1889., (480); 1s.(2p.)
- Jones, A. C. 2 A.D.s.:
  - [Richmond] 19 Mar 1863., (481); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same] 19 Mar 1863., (482); 1s.(2p.)
- Jones, David Rumph, 1825-1863. A.L.s. to Col. Edward Manigault; Charleston, 30 Apr 1861., (483); 1s.(2p.)
- Jones, John Marshall, 1820-1864. A.L.s. to Sanders Lansing Jr.; West Point, 14 Dec 1848., (484); 1s.(1p.)
- Jones, Samuel, 1819-1887. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Charleston, 22 Sep 1864., (485); 3s.(6p.)
  Report concerning transportation in Charleston Harbor.
- Jones, Samuel, 1819-1887. A.L.s. to Maxey Graham; Chattanooga, 28 Aug 1862., (486); 1s.(1p.)
- Jones, Samuel, 1819-1887. A.L.s. to Col. John B. Strange; Culpepper C. H., 23 May 1861., (487); 1s.(1p.)
- Jordan, E. C. A.L.s. to []; Baton Rouge, 1 Dec 1862., (488); 1s.(4p.)
  Endorsed by William Nelson Rector Beall.
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. A.L.s. to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Richmond, 21 Jul 1864., (489); 4s.(8p.)
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. A.L.s. to James Chesnut; Manassas, 31 Jul [1861], (490); 1s.(4p.)
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. A.L.s. to O. P. Faunin,; Allen Gay, and others; Charleston, 6 Nov 1862., (491); 1s.(2p.)
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. A.L.s. to Hugh Weedon Mercer; Charleston, 4 Nov 1862., (492); 1s.(4p.)
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. MS.L.s. to Rosewell Sabine Ripley; Charleston, 16 Sep 1863., (493); 1s.(2p.)
- Jordan, Thomas, 1819-1895. MS.L.s. (copy) to []; [n.p.] 10 Sep 1861., (494); 1s.(4p.)
- Kean, Robert Garlick Hill, 1828-1898. A.L.s. to Capt. H. V. Feugas; Richmond, 15 Jul 1864., (495); 1s.(1p.)
- Kean, Robert Garlick Hill, 1828-1898. A.L.s. to Burton N. Harrison; [Richmond] 25 Aug 1863., (496); 1s.(1p.)
- Kelly, John Herbert, 1840-1864. A.L.s. to Maj. E. S. Burford; [n.p.] 4 Jun 1864., (497); 1s.(2p.)
- Kemper, James Lawson, 1823-1895. A.L.s. to Edward Porter Alexander; Madison C.H., Va., 20 Sep 1869., (498); 2s.(5p.)
  Describes Pickett's charge and Gen. James Longstreet at the Battle of Gettysburg.
- Kemper, James Lawson, 1823-1895. 2 A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg:
  - Richmond, 29 Sep 1864., (499); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 30 Sep 1864., (500); 1s.(2p.)
- Kennedy, Daniel. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Castle Thunder Prison, 23 Mar 1863., (501); 1s.(3p.)
- Kennedy, John Doby, 1840-1896. A.L.s. to Henry Martyn Cist; Camden, S. C., 5 Apr 1890., (502); 1s.(1p.)
- Kershaw, Joseph Brevard, 1822-1894. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Picket Station, 22 Oct 1861., (503); 1s.(2p.)
- Kershaw, Joseph Brevard, 1822-1894. A.L.s. to James Chesnut; Fredericksburg, 3 Mar 1863., (504); 1s.(2p.)
- Kershaw, Joseph Brevard, 1822-1894. A.L.s. to Henry Martyn Cist; Waynesville, 17 Aug 1889., (505); 1s.(1p.)
- Keyes, Wade, b. 1821. A.L.s. to Christopher Gustavuus Memminger; Richmond, 14 Dec 1861., (506); 1s.(1p.)
- Kirkland, William Whedbee, 1833-1915. MS.L.s. to []; [n.p.] 1 May 1865., (507); 1s.(3p.)
- Kimbrough, Thomas M. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Richmond, 6 Jun 1863., (508); 1s.(3p.)
  Endorsed by Seddon.
- King, William Henry. A.L.s. to Marcus Joseph Wright; Austin, 12 Mar 1889., (509); 3s.(3p.)
- King, William Henry. MS.D.s.; Camp Rogers, La., 12 Feb 1864., (510); 1s.(2p.)
- Kirby, William. A.L.s. to Capt. R. B. Heuch; Fort Johnson, N.C., 9 Jan 1862., (511); 1s.(2p.)
- Kirby Smith, Edmund, 1824-1895. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; McCowan's Ferry, Ky., 7 Oct [1862?], (512); 1s.(4p.)
- Kirby Smith, Edmund, 1824-1895. 6 letters to Jefferson Davis:
  - Knoxville, 13 Aug 1862., (513); 1s.(1p.)
  - Flat Lick, Ky., 20 Oct 1862., (514); 1s.(3p.)
  - Shreveport, 11 Sep 1863., (515); 1s.(4p.)
  - Same, 8 Jun 1864., (516); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 22 Nov 1864., (517); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 13 Dec 1864., (518); 1s.(2p.)
- Kirby Smith, Edmund, 1824-1895. A.L.s. to [John Bankhead] Magruder; Hempstead, Tex., 26 May 1865., (519); 1s.(1p.)
- Kirby Smith, Edmund, 1824-1895. A.L.s. to []; Camp Colorado, 6 Jun 1860., (520); 1s.(3p.)
- Lamb, William. A.L.s. to William M Button & Co.; Fort Fisher, 16 Sep 1864., (521); 1s.(1p.)
- Lane, James Henry, 1833-1907. A.L.s. to John Letcher; Charlotte, 18 Apr 1861., (522); 1s.(3p.)
- Lane, Walter Paye, 1817-1892. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Marshall, 11 Nov 1875., (523); 1s.(1p.)
- Law, Evandor McIvor, 1836-1920. A.L.s. to Harry H. Hanson, Yorkville, S. C., 20 Dec 1886., (524); 1s. (1p.)
- Lawton, Alexander Robert, 1818-1896. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Savannah, 10 Aug 1866., (525); 6s. (12p.)
  Describes the occupation of Fort Pulaski.
- Lawton, Alexander Robert, 1818-1896. A.L.s. to []; Savannah, 15 Apr 1861., (526); 1s. (4p.)
- Leadbetter, Daniel, 1811-1866. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (527); 1s. (1p.)
- Lee, Edwin Gray, 1836-1870. A.D.s.; Staunton, 10 Nov 1864., (528); 1s. (1p.)
- Lee, Fitzhugh, 1835-1905. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; 15 May 1864., (529); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, George Washington Custis, 1832-1913. A.L.s. to Col. Lucius Bellinger Northrup; Richmond, 9 Feb 1864., (530); 1s. (1p.)
  Contains exerpt from letter of Joseph Eggleston Johnston concerning supplies for his army.
- Lee, George Washington Custis, 1832-1913. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; near Martinsburg, 25 Sep 1862., (531); 1s. (1p.)
  Report on condition of the army before and after the Battle of Sharpsburg.
- Lee, George Washington Custis, 1832-1913. 2 A.L.s. to John Henry Winder:
  - Atlanta, 27 Dec 1862., (532); 1s. (1p.)
  - Richmond, 6 Jun 1863., (533); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; [n.p.] 27 Jun 1862., (534); 1s. (2p.)
  Lee's report of the battle at Gaines' Mill (Cold Harbor).
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; near Winchester, 2 Oct 1862., (535); 2s. (5p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; [n.p.] 1 Apr 1865., (536); 1s. (2p.)
  Description of the danger of Grant's movement to Dinwiddie C. H.
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. MS.L.s. to Charles William Field; [n.p.] 17 Aug 1864., (537); 1s. (1p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. A.L.s. to Joseph Eggleston Johnston; Richmond, 23 May 1862., (538); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. A.L.s. to Francis Sprigg; near Petersburg, 7 Dec 1864., (539); 1s. (1p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder; [n.p.] 22 Apr 1863., (540); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, Robert Edward, 1807-1870. A.D.s.; Richmond, 24 Apr 1865., (541); 1s. (1p.)
  At bottom of MS.D.s. of Marsena Rudolph Patrick.
- Lee, Stephen Dill, 1833-1908. A.L.s. to James Birdseye McPherson; Jackson, 21 Jan 1864., (542); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, Stephen Dill, 1833-1908. A.L.s. to []; Columbus, Miss., 21 Jan 1902., (543); 1s. (1p.)
- Lee, Stephen Dill, 1833-1908. MS.D. (unsigned); [n.p.] 10 Apr 1865., (544); 1s. (2p.)
- Lee, Susan P. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Lexington, 20 Sep 1873., (545); 2s. (4p.)
  Concerns the military career of Edwin Gray Lee.
- Lee, William Henry Fitzhugh, 1837-1891. A.L.s. to [] Geter; [n.p.] 31 Mar 1862., (546); 1s. (1p.)
- Letcher, John, 1813-1884. MS.L.s. to [] Brackenbrough and [] Staples; Richmond, 12 May 1861., (547); 3s. (6p.)
- Letcher, John, 1813-1884. 2 MS.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - Richmond, 12 May 1861., (548); 1s. (1p.)
  - [Same] 13 Sep 1861., (549); 2s. (3p.)
- Letcher, John, 1813-1884. MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; [Richmond] 12 Sep 1861., (550); 1s. (3p.)
- Lewis, Joseph Horace, 1824-1904. A.L.s. to Maj. Albert W. Smith; Sylvania, 7 Feb 1865., (551); 1s. (2p.)
- Lewis, William Gaston, 1835-1901. A.L.s. to Charles [Colcock] Jones; Tarboro, 5 Jul 1871., (552); 1s. (2p.)
- Liddell, St. John Richardson, 1815-1870. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (553); 1s. (1p.)
- Lilley, Robert Doak, 1836-1886. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Louisville, 6 Nov 1871., (554); 1s. (3p.)
- Link, William A. A.L.s. to [Samuel Cooper]; Richmond, 10 Dec 1862., (555); 1s. (2p.)
- Little, Lewis Henry, 1817-1862. A.L.s. to Thomas Lowndes Snead; Saltillo, Miss., 9 Aug 1862., (556); 1s. (1p.)
- Logan, Thomas Muldrup, 1840-1914. A.L.s. to Col. []; [n.p.] 12 May 1864., (557); 1s. (2p.)
- Lovell, Mansfield, 1822-1884. MS.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Richmond, 28 Jul 1862., (558); 1s.(2p.)
- Lovell, Mansfield, 1822-1884. MS.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Jackson, 12 Jun 1862., (559); 1s.(2p.)
- Lovell, Mansfield, 1822-1884. A.L.s. to Maj. []; Columbia, 21 Apr 1865., (560); 1s.(1p.)
- Lomax, L. Q. C. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; San Antonio, 31 Dec 1862., (561); 1s.(4p.)
- Lomax, Lunsford Lindsay, 1835-1913. A.L.s. to Col. [] Farral; [n.p.] 3 Apr [1865?], (562); 1s.(1p.)
- Lomax, Lunsford Lindsay, 1835-1913. A.L.s. to John Letcher; Richmond, 23 Apr 1861., (563); 1s.(2p.)
- Lomax, Lunsford Lindsay, 1835-1913. A.L.s. to Col. John B. Sale; Hanover C.H., 24 May 1864., (564); 1s.(2p.)
- Longstreet, Augustus Baldwin, 1790-1870. A.L.s. to []; Columbia, 15 Mar 1861., (565); 1s.(2p.)
- Longstreet, James, 1821-1904. A.L.s. to Edward Porter Alexander; [n.p.] 4 Nov 1863., (566); 1s.(1p.)
- Longstreet, James, 1821-1904. A.L.s. to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Blackburnsford, July 1861., (567); 1s.(4p.)
- Longsreet, James, 1821-1904. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; [n.p.] 16 Oct 1863., (568); 1s.(3p.)
- Longstreet, James, 1821-1904. 2 A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - [N.p.] 15 Mar 1864., (569); 1s.(15p.)
  - Bristol, 2 Apr 1864., (570); 1s.(1p.)
- Longstreet, James, 1821-1904. A.L.s. to Thomas Jordan; Blackburn, 23 Jul 1861., (571); 1s.(2p.)
- Loring, William Wing, 1818-1886. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Charleston, 15 Sep 1862., (572); 1s.(2p.)
- Loring, William Wing, 1818-1886. MS.L. (telegram) to Daniel Ruggles; Meridian, 25 Apr 1863., (573); 1s.(2p.)
- Loring, William Wing, 1818-1886. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Valley Mountain, 8 Aug 1861., (574); 1s.(2p.)
- Lowrey, Mark Perrin, 1828-1885. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Ripley, Miss., 28 Feb 1872., (575); 1s.(2p.)
- Lowrey, Robert, 1830-1910. A.L.s. to [Charles Colcock Jones]; Brandon, Miss., 14 May 1872., (576); 1s.(1p.)
- Lubbock, Francis Richard, 1815-1905. 4 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Austin, 26 Jun 1862., (577); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 27 Jun 1862., (578); 1s.(4p.)
  - [Same] 28 Jul 1862., (579); 1s.(3p.)
  - Richmond, 29 Dec 1864., (580); 1s.(3p.)
    With the latter is a reply by Jefferson Davis.
- Lynch, N. L.? A.L.s. to Lt. [] Smith; Aquia Creek, 31 May [186-?]., (581); 1s.(2p.)
- Lyon, Hylan Benton, 1836-1907. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Frankfort, 8 Jul 1872., (582); 1s.(4p.)
- Mabry, H. P. A.L.s. to Gen. []; near Saltillo, Miss., 22 Aug 1862., (583); 1s.(2p.)
- Maccabbin, Samuel. A.L.s. to Maj. []; [n.p., n.d.], (584); 2s.(4p.)
- McCausland, John W., 1836-1927. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Fort Pleasant, Va., 27 Mar 1874., (585); 1s.(1p.)
- McCausland, John W., 1836-1927. MS.L. (telegram) to Samuel Cooper; New River Bridge, 9 May 1864., (586); 1s.(2p.)
- McComb, William, 1828-1918. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Gordonsville, Va., 13 Jan 1892., (587); 1s.(2p.)
- McCown, John Porter, 1815-1829. A.D.s.; Knoxville, 12 Sept 1862., (588); 1s.(1p.)
- McCray, Thomas H. A.L.s. to Maj. H. S. Bradford; near Shelbyville, 20 Apr 1863., (589); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Alexander Peter Stewart.
- McCreary, James Bennett, 1838-1918. Photograph s.; [n.p., n.d.], (590); 1s.(1p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. A.L.s. to Andrew B. Moore; Washington, 25 Jul 1860., (591); 2s.(6p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. A.L.s. to Sterling Price; Fort Smith, Ark., 7 Feb 1862., (592); 1s.(1p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. A.L.s. to John Henninger Reagan; Boston Mountain, Ark., 20 Mar 1862., (593); 1s.(4p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. A.L.s. to Henry []; Florence, Ala., 11 Nov 1860., (594); 1s.(4p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. MS.L.s. to Gen. []; Camp Johnson, Ark., 16 Nov 1861., (595); 1s.(1p.)
- McCulloch, Ben, 1811-1862. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Sequin, Tex., 15 Jul 1891., (596); 2s.(5p.)
- McGowan, Samuel, 1819-1897. A.L.s. to Maj. Joseph A. Engelhard; [n.p.] 26 Jan 1865., (597); 1s.(2p.)
- McGowan, Samuel, 1819-1897. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Abbeville C. H., S. C., 24 May 1871., (598); 1s.(3p.)
- McGowan, Samuel, 1819-1897. A.D.s.; Citadel, 10 Apr 1861., (599); 1s.(2p.)
- McIntosh, James [McQueen], 1828-1862. A.L.s. to John []; near Fort Klarney, Ky., 18 Jun 1858., (600); 1s.(4p.)
- Mackall, William Whann, 1817-1897. A.L.s. to Col. []; Dalton, 22 Mar 1864., (601); 1s.(4p.)
- McKay, Thomas H. A.L.s. to Col. R. H. Cole; near Culpeper C. H., 29 Jul 1863., (602); 1s.(2p.)
- McKissick, Isaac G. MS.L. (unsigned copy) to Capt. I. H. Plarce; Bottom's Bridge, 25 Jul 1863., (603); 1s.(2p.)
- McLaws, Lafayette, 1821-1897. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (604); 1s.(1p.)
- Maclay, Robert P. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (605); 1s.(1p.)
- McMurry, S. A. A.L.s. to W. W. Cluskey; Tupelo, 16 Jun 1862., (606); 1s.(2p.)
- McNair, E. MS.D.s.; Memphis, 27 Apr 1862., (607); 1s.(2p.)
- McRae, Colin J. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; London, 8 Aug 1863., (608); 3s.(5p.)
- McRae, Dandridge, 1829-1899. A.D.s.; near Helma? 4 Jul 1863., (609); 1s.(1p.)
- McRae, Dandridge. MS.D.s.; Jacksonport, Ark., 9 Jun 1863., (610); 1s.(2p.)
- MacRae, William, 1834-1882. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Macon, 1 Jun 1871., (611); 1s.(1p.)
- Magoffin, Beriah, 1815-1885. A.L.s. to George Nicholas Sanders; Frankfort, 24 Mar 1861., (612); 1s.(3p.)
- Magoffin, Beriah, 1815-1885. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Frankfort, 17 Apr 1861., (613); 1s.(1p.)
  Letter of introduction for William Preston Johnston.
- Magruder, John Bankhead, 1810-1871. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 26 Apr 1861., (614); 2s.(8p.)
- Magruder, John Bankhead, 1810-1871. 2 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Near San Patricio, 10 Apr 1863., (615); 1s.(4p.)
  - Shreveport, 10 May 1864., (616); 1s.(3p.)
- Magruder, John Bankhead, 1810-1871. A.L.s. to Lt. [] Dubois; [n.p.] 18 Apr 1861., (617); 1s.(2p.)
- Magruder, John Bankhead, 1810-1871. A.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Richmond, 11 Sep 1862., (618); 1s.(3p.)
- Mahone, William, 1826-1895. A.L.s. to Samuel A. Christie; Petersburg, 12 Dec 1888., (619); 5s.(10p.)
  Account of the Confederate Army at Sailor's Creek en route to Appamattox.
- Mahone, William, 1826-1895. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; [n.p.] 18 Jul 1863., (620); 1s.(2p.)
  Letter of resignation. Endorsed by Ambrose Powell Hill,; Robert Edward Lee and James Alexander Seddon.
- Major, Jones Patrick, 1836-1877. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (621); 1s.(1p.)
- Mallory, Stephen Russell, 1813-1873. MS.L.s. to Thomas Stanley Bocock; Richmond, 16 Dec 1861., (622); 1s.(2p.)
- Mallory, Stephen Russell, 1813-1873. 5 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Richmond, 31 March 1862., (623); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 12 Jun 1862., (624); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 27 Sep 1862., (625); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 14 Oct 1864., (626); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 24 Dec 1864., (627); 2s.(3p.)
- Mallory, Stephen Russell, 1813-1873. MS.L. (unsigned copy) to Capt. French Forrest; Richmond, 11 Jun 1862., (628); 2s.(3p.)
- Mallory, Stephen Russell, 1813-1873. Printed D.s.; Richmond, 11 Jun 1861., (629); 1s.(1p.)
- Mallory, Stephen Russell, 1813-1873. MS.D.s.; [Richmond], 16 Dec 1861., (630); 1s.(1p.)
- Maney, George [Earl], 1826-1901. A.L.s. to Col. Thomas McQuick? [n.p.] 26 Jul, (631); 1s.(1p.)
- Maney, George Earl, 1826-1901. MS.D.s.; near Chatanooga, 30 Jul 1863., (632); 1s.(1p.)
- Manigault, Arthur Middleton, 1824-1886. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Georgetown, S.C., 10 Jun 1871., (633); 1s.(1p.)
- Mann, Ambrose Dudley, 1801-1889. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; London, 20 Apr 1861., (634); 2s.(4p.)
- Manney, J. A.L.s. to Gen [] Jackson; [n.p.] 19 Jul 1861., (635); 1s.(1p.)
- Marks, H. B. Signed photograph; [n.d.], (636); 1s.(1p.)
- Marmaduke, John Sappington, 1833-1887. A.L.s. to William Preston Johnston; Fort Warren, 29 Jan 1865., (637); 1s.(1p.)
- Marmaduke, John Sappington, 1833-1887. A.L.s. to St. Col. [] Mac Gill? [n.p.] 6 Sep 1864., (638); 1s.(1p.)
- Marmaduke, John Sappington, 1833-1887. MS.D.s.; Princeton, Ark., 29 Aug 1864., (639); 1s.(2p.)
- Marshall, Humphry, 1812-1872. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Tazwell Co., Va., 25 Jul 1862., (640); 1s.(3p.)
- Marshall, John, d. 1862. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; 13 Jun 1861., (641); 1s.(2p.)
- Martin, James Green, 1819-1878. A.L.s. to Henry T. Clark; Camp Sidney Johnston, 25 Jun 1862., (642); 1s.(2p.)
- Martin, James Green, 1819-1878. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Asheville, 8 Jun 1872., (643); 1s.(4p.)
- Martin, James Green, 1819-1878. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Raleigh, 27 Sep 1862., (644); 1s.(2p.)
- Martin, John D. A.L.s. to Capt. [] Schaumburg; Baldwin, 23 Sep 1862., (645); 1s.(1p.)
- Martin, Theodore P. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; [] 22 Oct 1872., (646); 1s.(1p.)
- Martin, William Thompson, 1823-1910. 2 A.L.s. to Maj. E.S. Bruford:
  - [N.p.] 16 May 1863., (647); 1s.(1p.)
  - [N.p.] 19 Jun 1863., (648); 1s.(1p.)
- Martin, William Thompson, 1823-1910. 2 A.L.s. to Joseph Wheeler:
  - [N.p.] 20 Jun 1863., (649); 1s.(4p.)
  - Alexandria, Ala., 27 Jun 1863., (650); 1s.(3p.)
- Mason, James Murray, 1792-1871. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Paris, 13 Apr 1864., (651); 2s.(5p.)
- Massey, B. F. MS.D.s.; Jefferson City, 11 May 1861., (652); 1s.(3p.)
  An act authorizing the Governor of Missouri to suppress rebellion and repel invasion.
- Matthews, James Muscoe, b. 1822. A.L.s. to James E. Tayler; Richmond, 1 Mar 1889., (653); 1s.(3p.)
- Matthews, Robert A. A.D.s.; [Richmond] 5 Oct 1861., (654); 1s.(1p.)
- Maury, Dabney Herndon, 1822-1900. A.L.s. to William A. Buker?; Mobile, 10 Jun 1866., (655); 1s.(1p.)
- Maury, Dabney Herndon, 1822-1900. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Mobile, 5 Mar 1864., (656); 1s.(3p)
- Maury, Dabney Herndon, 1822-1900. A.L.s. to []; Vicksburg, 27 Jan 1863., (657); 1s.(2p.)
- Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1806-1873. M.L.s. to William Bond and Son; Washington, 20 Dec 1860., (658); 1s.(1p.)
- Maury, Matthew Fontaine, 1806-1873. A.L.s. to []; [n.p.] May 1872., (659); 1s.(1p.)
- Maxey, Samuel Bell, 1825-1895. A.L.s. to William Robertson Boggs; Fort Lawson, 27 May 1864., (660); 1s.(4p.)
- Maxey, Samuel Bell, 1825-1895. A.L.s. to Sterling Price; Fort Lawson, 14 Nov 1864., (661); 1s.(2p.)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus, 1803-1888. MS.L.s. to Robert Woodward Barnwell; Richmond, 28 Mar 1862., (662); 2s.(3p.)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus, 1803-1888. MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 22 Aug 1863., (663); 1s.(4p.)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus, 1803-1888. 2 A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Richmond, 2 Jun 1864., (664); 1s.(3p.)
  - Hot Rock, 23 Aug 1864., (665); 1s.(4p.)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus, 1803-1888. A.L.s. to Burton N. Harrison; [Richmond] 27 Sep 1862., (666); 1s.(2p.)
- Memminger, Christopher Gustavus, 1803-1888. A.L.s. to George Wythe Randolph; Richmond, 17 Oct 1862., (667); 1s.(2p.)
- Mercer, Hugh Weedon, 1808-1877. MS.L.s. to Joseph Emerson Brown; Savannah, 25 Apr 1863., (668); 1s.(1p.)
- Miles, William Porcher, 1822-1899. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Yazoo City, 9 Nov 1875., (669); 1s.(2p.)
- Miller, William, 1820-1909. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Pensacola, 8 Jul 1872., (670); 1s.(2p.)
- Milton, John, 1807-1865. 3 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Tallahassee, 20 Aug 1862., (671); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 18 Aug 1863., (672); 3s.(10p.)
  - Same, 25 Feb 1865., (673); 1s.(2p.)
- Moore, Andrew B. Printed D.s.; Montgomery, 20 Sep 1860., (674); 1s.(1p.)
- Moore, John Creed, 1824-1910. MS.L.s. to Thomas Lownder Snead; Tupelo, 19 Sep 1862., (675); 1s.(3p.)
- Moore, John Creed, 1824-1910. MS.L.s. to Lloyd Tilghman; Tupelo, 20 Sep 1862., (676); 1s.(4p.)
  Endorsed by Tilghman.
- Moore, Patrick Theodore, 1821-1883. A.L.s. to [Charles Colcock Jones]; Richmond, 9 Dec 1875., (677); 1s.(3p.)
- Moore, Samuel Preston, 1813-1889. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 28 Apr 1864., (678); 1s.(2p.)
- Moore, Samuel Preston, 1813-1889. MS.D.s.; Richmond, 25 Apr 1863., (679); 1s.(2p.)
- Moore, Samuel Preston, 1813-1889. A. endorsement s.; [n.p.] 3 Mar 1863., (680); 1s.(1p.)
- Moore, Thomas Overton, 1804-1876. 7 letters to Jefferson Davis:
  - Opelousas, 2 Jun 1862., (681); 2s.(5p.)
  - Same, 12 Jun 1862., (682); 2s.(4p.)
  - Baton Rouge, 20 Jul 1862., (683); 1s.(2p.)
  - Opelousas, 23 Jul 1862., (684); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 4 Aug 1862., (685); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 12 Sep 1862., (686); 2s.(4p.)
  - Alexandria, 11 Nov 1862., (687); 2s.(4p.)
    The last endorsed by James Alexander Seddon.
- Morgan, John Hunt, 1825-1864. A.L.s. to William Montague Browne, Richmond, 22 Jan 1864., (688); 1s.(1p.)
- Morgan, John Hunt, 1825-1864. A.L.s. to Simon Bolivar Buckner; [n.p.] 20 Nov 1862., (689); 1s.(2p.)
- Morgan, John Tyler, 1824-1907. MS.L.s. to John Cabell Breckinridge, Natasulga, Ala., 31 Mar 1865., (690); 1s.(3p.)
- Morgan, William E. A.L.s. [fragment] to Capt. W.Y.C. Humes; [n.p., n.d.], (691); 1s.(2p.)
- Morton, Richard. A.L.s. to John Cabell Breckinridge; Richmond, 1 Mar 1865., (692); 2s.(3p.)
- Mosby, John Singleton, 1833-1916. Cut autograph; [n.p., n.d.], (693); 1s.(1p.)
- Mouton, Alfred, 1829-1864. A.L.s. to Capt. Roy Mason Hove; near Petersburg, 2 Mar 1862., (694); 1s.(2p.)
- Munford, Thomas T. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; [] 12 Sep 1873., (695); 1s.(4p.)
- Murphy, Isaac, 1802-1882. A.L.s. (fragment); [n.p.] 20 May 1864., (696); 1s.(1p.)
- Murrah, Pendleton. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Austin, 25 Jun 1864., (697); 1s.(4p.)
- Myers, A. C. A.L.s. [fragment] to []; [n.p., n.d.], (698); 1s.(1p.)
- Myers, Charles D. MS.D.s.; Petersburg, 9 May 1863., (699); 1s.(1p.)
- Neel, T. J. MS.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Gily Co., Va., 5 May 1864., (700); 1s.(1p.)
  Also signed by St. P. F. Fisher and St. G.A.T. Grossclose.
- Nelson, Allison, 1822-1862. A.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (701); 1s.(1p.)
- Nelson, George E. W. A.L.s. to [John Henry] Winder; Richmond, 13 Jul 1863., (702); 1s.(2p.)
- Nicholls, Francis Redding Tillou, 1834-1912. A.L.s. to [Charles Colcock Jones]; Parish of Assumption, La., 10 Jul 1872., (703); 2s.(7p.)
- Northrup, Lucius Bellinger, 1811-1894. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; [n.p.] 9 Apr 1864., (704); 1s.(1p.)
- Northrup, Lucius Bellinger, 1811-1894. A.L.s. to [Jefferson?] Davis; [n.p.] 6 Aug 1864., (705); 1s.(3p.)
- Offutt, H. St. George. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 17 Jun 1862., (706); 1s.(1p.)
- O'Neal, Edward Asbury, 1818-1890. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; Florence, 10 Jun 1874., (707); 1s.(1p.)
- Orr, Henry E. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; [n.p.] 30 Nov 1864., (708); 1s.(1p.)
- Otey, John M. MS.D.s.; Jackson, Tenn., 24 Feb 1802., (709); 1s.(2p.)
- Ould, Robert. A.L.s. to [] Blanton; Richmond, 9 Dec 1862., (710); 1s.(1p.)